

# **Europass Curriculum Vitae**

My LinkedIN profile





#### Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

Telephone

Personal Email

Nationality

Date of birth

Gender

## **Buracchi Marco**

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy

+39 3498362954

Personal: ma.buracchi@gmail.com PEC: marco.buracchi@postecert.it

19/12/1985

Italian

Male

Bio

I'm an ICS CyberSecurity Specialist at H-ON Consulting in Prato and I attend the Short Specialisation Programme (Master I livello) in Cybersecurity at the Pisa University. I graduated in October 2018 with 110/110 cum laude at the master's degree in computer science, "resilient and secure cyber physical systems" curricula. My master thesis was on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I obtained the bachelor degree in computer science in 2015 with 110/110 cum laude.

# **Desired employment/** Occupational field

### **Education and training**

**Dates** 

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects

Occupational skills covered

Name and type of organization providing education and training Dates

Title of qualification awarded

## IT/OT/IoT security, Software Development & Research

02/2019 - 03/2020 (expected)

Short Specialisation Programme - Master I livello in cybersecurity

Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network Security & Ethical hacking, Operating Systems Security, Digital Forensics, Cyber Intelligence, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity, Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Risk monitoring for networks and applications. Secure application development (network, mobile, cloud)

Expert in security analysis of applications and IT systems, expert in cyber attacks analysis

University of Pisa, Department of Information Engineering

CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche) - Institute of Informatics and Telematics 01/10/2015 - 12/10/2018

Master's degree (Laurea Magistrale) in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed programming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced numerical analysis

Name and type of organization providing education and training Level in national classification

University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude

Dates

08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

skills covered

Name and type of organization

Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning, programming languages, and verification

Name and type of organization providing education and training

Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of Maryland

Dates

01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered Bachelor's Degree (Laurea Triennale) in Computer Science.

Algorithms and data structures, Calculus I and II, Computer architecture, Computer networks, Computing and management, Concurrent programming, Databases and information systems, Discrete mathematics and mathematical logic, Human-Machine interaction, Information retrieval and semantic web technologies, Interpreters and compilers, Linear Algebra, Numerical analysis, Operating systems, Physics, Probability theory and statistics, Programming methodologies, Theoretical computer science

Name and type of organization providing education and training Level in national or classification University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude.

# Work experiences

Dates

13/02/2020 - now

Occupation or position held

ICS CyberSecurity Specialist

Main activities

ICS CyberSecurity consulting, R&D

Name and address of employer

H-ON consulting, Via Lepanto, 23, 59100 Prato PO

Type of business or sector

ICS CyberSecurity

Dates

01/10/2019 - now

Occupation or position held

Junior Security Engineer

Main activities

Vulnerability assessment, penetration testing, research and development.

Name and address of employer

Florence Consulting Group, Via Luciano Lama, 23, 50019 Sesto Fiorentino FI

Type of business or sector

IT Security

Dates

28/11/2018 - 31/08/2019

Occupation or position held

Private tutor

Main activities

One-on-one in-house tutoring for middle-school, high-scool and university students.

Name and address of employer

Centro didattico Matemagia - Via Baracca 166, Firenze

Type of business or sector

Private education

Dates

01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016

Occupation or position held

Research helper

Main activities and responsibilities

I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the time in the smart grid and smart cities. http://amadeos-project.eu/

Name and address of employer
Type of business or sector

Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems

Dates

Occupation or position held

or position held CNC Machinist and Programmer

Main activities AutoCAD drawing, CNC program

AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser cutting, machining center, wire EDM)

Name and address of employer

Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008) Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012)

Type of business or sector

Manufacturing industry

01/05/2006 - 01/09/2012

Dates

01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006

Occupation or position held

Technical employee

Main activities and responsibilities

Direct measurement in field, fixture designer, autoCAD drawing, cutting programs developer

Name and address of employer
Type of business or sector

Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy Manufacturing industry

# Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue
Other language(s)
Self-assessment
European level(\*)

**English** 

#### Italian

Understanding				Speaking			Writing		
Listening		Reading		Spoken interaction		Spoken production			
C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user

<sup>(\*)</sup> Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Computer skills and competences

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Good knowledge in the use of Kali Linux OS and various IT security and cyber intelligence tools (among the best known: Metasploit, OpenVAS, Nessus, Legion, Maltego). High expertise with many tools such as Apache NiFi, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework.

Artistic skills and competences

I studied piano at conservatoire for 4 years. I can play guitar. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driving licence(s)

Driver's license (Italian Republic, full European validity), category A (motorcycle owner) and B (car owner).

## **Additional informations**

#### References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it; Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it;

#### **Personal interests**

IT security, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and all kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003 and GDPR 679/16 art.13)

Signature:

Mours Funti